Guide to the Susan L. Clark papers, 1976-1990 MS 460
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Susan L. Clark papers
1976-1990
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Clark, Susan L.
MS 460
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
This collection consists of correspondence, research notes, and published articles and manuscripts related to German and Slavic Studies by Rice University professor Susan L. Clark, as well as some co-authored by her colleague Julian M. Wasserman. Collection Date Range: 1976-1990. This collection is 1.5 linear feet (3 boxes).
Biographical / Historical
Susan Louise Clark, professor of German and Slavic Studies at Rice University, was born April 21, 1948 in Canton, Ohio. She graduated from Mount Union College in Alliance, Ohio, and received a doctoral degree in Comparative Literature from Rutgers University in 1973. She came directly to Rice University and, in 1985, was promoted to Full Professor of German and Slavic Studies. She was a member of numerous professional organizations, and was highly regarded as a feminist scholar.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of correspondence, research notes, and published articles and manuscripts related to German and Slavic Studies by Susan L. Clark, as well as some co-authored by her colleague Julian M. Wasserman.
Susan Louise Clark, professor of German and Slavic Studies at Rice University, was born April 21, 1948 in Canton, Ohio. She graduated from Mount Union College in Alliance, Ohio, and received a doctoral degree in Comparative Literature from Rutgers University in 1973. She came directly to Rice University and, in 1985, was promoted to Full Professor of German and Slavic Studies. She was a member of numerous professional organizations, and was highly regarded as a feminist scholar.
Dates: 1976-1990. Quantity: 1.5 linear ft. (3 boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Susan L. Clark estate, August 1997.
Accruals
No more materials are expected to be added to this collection.
Index Terms
Subjects
Authors; College teachers; Language and languages; Rice University -- History; Literature
- Series I: Correspondence, 188605
  - Correspondence, 1984-1985, 58669 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Research notes, 188606
  - Research notes, Undated; 58670 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Research performance/chronological listing of works, 1990 and undated, 58671 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series III: Works, 188607
  - Anonymous article by Susan L. Clark, "In Die Klage…", Date Unknown.; 58672 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Published articles by Susan L. Clark, 1976-1983, 58673 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Published articles by Susan L. Clark and Julian Wasserman, 1978-1986, 58674 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Published articles by Susan L. Clark and Julian Wasserman, 1976-1984, 58675 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Published article by Susan L. Clark and David Duewall, 1981, 58676 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reviews by Susan L. Clark, 1979-1990, 58677 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Reviews of Susan L. Clark's works, 1985-1992, 58678 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Baroque Women Writers article on Schwartz, draft, undated, 58679 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - A Sense of Property: Midwest and Money in the Novels of Mabel Seeley, 1979, 58680 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hartmannn's Iwein: Strife in the Landscape of the Mind, typescript, undated, 58681 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Paul Fleming's Palinode and the Killing of Death, print proof, undated, 58682 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Hartmann's Erec: Language, Perception, and Transformation, typescript, undated, 58683 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Genelun erbleichte harte;" The Dark Figure and Responsibility for Carnage in Das Rolandslied, typescript, undated, 58684 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Hartmann's Landscape of the Mind, typescript, undated, 58685 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Arthur Schnitzler's Der Grune Kakadu (incomplete and completed typescript versions), undated, 58686 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Horribicribfrifax, typescript, undated, 58687 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - " Ir Wizzet Wol:" Knowledge in Hartmann's Gregorius, typescript, undated, 58688 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - An Introduction to the Work of Ruth Rendell (incomplete), typescript, undated, 58689 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Foreign language drama… "Dulcitius", typescript, undated, 58690 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "The Soul as a Salmon", typescript, undated, 58691 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "St. Erkenwald's Spiritual Itinerary," typescript, undated, 58692 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Thomas Hardy and the Tristan Legend," typescript, undated, 58693 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - From Cornwall to Wessex: Tess of the D'Urbervilles and The Famous Tragedy of the Queen of Cornwall", typescript, undated, 58694 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Pearl-Poet: A study in Artistic Unity, 1980, typescript & editorial correspondence, 58695 (Box 3, Folder 1)